What's going on?
What is this?
These iceblades are merely emblems;
they are not my true nature.
What?
Give your professor a
proper answer, Ray White!
These are nothing more than symbols tied
to the name of the Iceblade Sorcerer.
Make sense, damn it!
Deceleration.
Lock registration!
Why?!
Let's have a lesson, Professor Gray.
What is the biggest difference
between fire and ice-based sorcery?
What? I'm the professor.
What a foolish query.
The main difference between
fire and ice sorcery
is whether code is used to accelerate or
decelerate the particles' vibrations.
That's correct,
I expected nothing less from you.
In other words, ice sorcery
utilizes deceleration.
Many sorcerers only execute that processing
on a subconscious level.
But I have created code so intricate
that I am able to control both
deceleration and anchoring
with such precision that an average
person could never emulate it.
Then, using antimaterial code,
I am able to reverse the
code theory itself,
and revert all spells back to prima materia.
What?
Antimaterial code?
But no one's ever done that successfully!
Don't you understand?
Before me, all sorcery returns to the void.
That is the true nature of the
current Iceblade Sorcerer.
Material shift, ice sword!
Damn it.
I even used the Dark Triad...
This can't be happening!
What kind of sorcery is that?!
I don't know!
Could that be...?!
Mind infiltration sorcery...
Hey, doesn't Ray look odd?
His body...
It's getting covered in ice.
You're not in control
of your power, are you?
I can do this.
Die, Iceblade!
Ray!
Even if you are the Iceblade...
Ice Bloom Profusion!
No! No!
Wow.
Professor Gray, let's have
you rest there for now.
Deceleration.
Chronos Lock, activate.
Ray!
I protected them.
Nobody was lost.
So it's fine now, right, Master?
The Iceblade Sorcerer
Shall Rule the World
Episode 5
The Boy Who Became the World's Strongest Sorcerer Has an Unexpected Meeting on the Battlefield
Are you all right?
Hey, hey!
Hang on! I'll save you!
Lydia, who's that kid?
When did you become a mom, Lydia?
Why do you go there, Dumbpink?
I'm still...
Still what, I wonder?
Colonel! Lydia's...
Ainsworth, could you please let
us know what's going on here?
I heard a voice crying out to me,
so I searched the area and found this child.
It looks like he's the only survivor.
What?! They're refusing to take him in?!
He's a war orphan from this country!
It seems like the village
he's from is special.
What does that mean?
It's a completely independent
domain inside the country.
Apparently, the government's stance
is complete non-intervention.
So they're saying that
child is not a citizen?
That's ridiculous!
That village is rumored to be cursed.
Cursed?
Something about performing rituals
to call gods into mediums and such.
Are people really still talking
about curses and gods?
I mean ceremonies and religion
still exist in the Kingdom, as well.
A dwindling few.
Since the code theory was discovered,
even magic was once considered
supernatural before it became sorcery.
If the research continues at the current rate,
we might even uncover the
true meaning of the world.
But for people to go on living,
some things need to be hidden, as well.
I won't deny there are
psychological benefits.
Oh, right.
What?
I hear he's regained consciousness.
Why didn't you say that first, you idiot?!
And what's your name?
Carol!
Lydia.
What's his status?
He's stable, but...
What's your name?
It's no use.
Ray.
So your name is Ray?!
Yeah.
My name is Lydia.
Lydia Ainsworth.
Lydia...
Let's play ball!
Huh?
Carol, what are you doing?
Becoming great friends
with Ray, that's what!
Today, I've been reading him picture books.
Ray, can you say my name?
Carol.
But I told you, you can call me Carocaro!
Now, why don't you try saying,
"I love you, Carocaro"?
Carol.
Ray, it seems you already know how
this Dumbpink should be treated.
It's not funny, Lydia!
Huh?
He laughed just now.
He laughed, right?
It seemed like that, yeah.
Hey, Ray, I'll tell you about
my legendary acts of bravery!
Not that again!
Shut up, Dumbpink.
Pffff!
Lydia, about Ray....
Have you found anywhere we could leave him?
No.
What should I do?
You're not thinking of taking him yourself?
Of course not.
We're soldiers.
Of course I wasn't considering that.
But I don't know what that
Dumbpink will say.
No way!
Ray is staying with me!
Oh, boy.
Caroline, you understand that's
impossible, right?
It is possible!
I have money! I could feed him!
We have a mission.
Then I'll take him to my own house,
but I'm not abandoning him!
I do understand where Carol's coming from,
but there's nothing—
That's not true!
We're sorry.
And what about you two?
As you say, Colonel,
I believe he should be given to an
orphanage or adopted by someone.
And you, Ainsworth?
I...
Ray.
Ray, what do you want to do?
You heard us talking, right?
I want to stay with you.
Colonel.
What is it?
My family, specifically
my elder sister's family,
has a daughter close to Ray's age.
Carol and Abbie will help, too.
I will take responsibility for him.
Is there something about Ray that's
prompted you to go such lengths?
There is, which is exactly why I
believe he needs proper guidance.
I understand.
So long as this does not affect your
duties, you have my permission.
Oh, thank goodness!
Ray, you're going to stay with us forever!
Ray,
from now on you'll be staying with me.
No, with us.
Together?
Yeah.
Okay.
Which means that from
now on, I'm your master.
Master?
That's right! You are my apprentice!
I will be teaching you everything I know.
Okay! Got it, Master!
Six Years Later
Far East War
Front Inside the Republic of Merth
Captain, we're done for!
Everyone, retreat!
Icicle Blades!
Complete annihilation confirmed.
Impressive.
All right, then. We'll let the
soldiers take over after this.
Right, they're waiting for us.
That was a kid, right?
So those are the Arnold Kingdom army's Astrals?
This is Correine.
Subjugation complete.
We're heading back.
Overheating.
What an awful sight.
Excessive use of sorcery,
the stress from being in an environment
where death is omnipresent...
It's like battlefields were
designed to cause overheating.
Rampant power that you
can't control.
The only thing that follows is
the destruction of your mind.
A disease veritably caused
by modern sorcery.
Yes.
It can happen to any sorcerer
on the battlefield.
To anyone.
So, this is the situation at the moment.
The sorcerers Konpeki and Raimei
have both been confirmed dead.
Of the Seven Grands?!
So there's someone powerful
enough to do that?!
I suppose that means it's certain that the
Aywell Empire is intervening in this war.
From here on, the battle lines
will only get more fierce.
Even us Astrals may not get away unscathed.
I want you all to redouble your focus.
Ray, you are still young.
You could still go back, if you want.
Captain Correine...
That's right. You're the same age as my son.
That's not an age to be on the battlefield.
My master taught me that people
with talent have a responsibility.
I consider this unit to be like a family...
No, you are my family.
Commander Henrick, Captain Correine.
Colonel Garnet.
Derek, Howard.
Master.
And Carol, I guess.
Ray!
I've prepared for this
ever since I enlisted.
If anything happens to
you, I'll come save ya!
Howard...
Howard!
Ray, don't!
Ray, you go and live.
For now, I'll go up into this
wide sky and watch you grow.
No, Howard!
Live, Ray.
Ray, are you all right?
Master...
I...
Looks like you used it.
I'm very sorry.
Don't be.
I would have done the same.
Don't worry about it too much.
In the end, it all went well.
At some point, you'll no longer
need the Chronos Lock.
That reminds me! Everyone...
Is fine.
It seems they only suffered from a
slight magical energy deficiency.
Everyone's already recovered.
You did well, Ray.
Anyway, I'm glad that you're okay.
Come visit me again when
you've got some time.
Yes, Master.
Yup.
Miss Carla?
Your ear, please.
Miss Lydia was very worried about you.
Please get some rest.
Good bye.
I was against it, at first.
Huh?
Against you attending the school.
I thought you needed more rest.
Even among the other sorcery
academies in our country,
ours is especially full of people
preoccupied with bloodlines.
An ordinary like yourself
would only be unhappy.
Raised on the battlefield,
touched by so many deaths.
After all you've been through,
I couldn't stand the thought of
putting you into an environment
full of the discrimination from the nobles.
Miss Abbie...
But then Lydia came and bowed her head.
My master did?
Her and I go way back, but this was
the first time she's ever done that.
Ray is even stronger and kinder
than we ever imagined.
That's why I want him to know
that there's more to this world.
The good and the bad...
I want him to learn how to feel,
how to think, and how to live.
What Ray needs now is not us adults,
and especially not the battlefield.
He needs everyday experiences
appropriate for a boy his age.
Ray doesn't have friends his own age.
I mean, I had you, and I guess Carol.
So that's you want him here?
He...
He deserves to find happiness.
Lydia...
Abbie, please.
Master...
I'm so glad Ray is okay!
I'm glad, too.
Ray, enjoy your life at school.
Find your own happiness.
That is our wish for you.
And Lydia's.
I will.
Go ahead.
You came to visit me.
Sure.
Are you... all right?
Yes.
I see. I'm glad.
Um...
I'm sorry.
I kept my secret from you.
I am one of the seven grand sorcerers,
the Iceblade Sorcerer.
I... see.
Having fought alongside my master
and the others in the Far East War,
I overheated in the final battle.
Overheated?
It's when you lose control of your engram.
I myself don't entirely understand
what exactly happened.
But when I regained consciousness,
I saw that everything around
me had become a wasteland.
My bleeding master had her arms around me.
Even now, I am using a spell called
Chronos Lock to keep from overheating.
So is this maybe the reason
you're not so good at sorcery?
That's correct.
I lost many precious friends in battle
and I caused my master grievous injuries.
Of course, even though they were our enemies,
I took countless numbers of their lives, as well.
I hid my blood-soaked
past and I deceived you.
I am...
My hands are stained with blood.
Do I have the right to be near you at all?
I've been thinking about it the entire time.
I am truly sorry.
I want you to be here.
Amelia...
No matter what happened in your past,
I believe in the person you are right now.
I know that you are an
extremely kind person.
That's right!
You're an amazing person and my best bud!
And that's not going to change,
no matter what happened in your past.
I'll always be with you, too!
I mean, you're my friend!
Jeez.
I can't believe you spent
time worrying about this.
W-We're friends!
Ray!
We all want to stay with you.
You're not alone.
Thank you, all.
Good evening,
Mr. Alium.
Ray White.
What are you doing here at this hour?
I needed to apologize.
I've done things that can
never be taken back.
I accept your apology.
It's water under the bridge.
But that's...
You acknowledged your shortcomings
and delivered an honest apology.
I think that alone is truly amazing.
You really felt that remorse
deep in your heart.
That's why you're here.
Or am I wrong, Albert?
White...
You can call me Ray.
But...!
That's what I'd like you to call me.
I just can't win.
How can you be so strong and
never stray from your path?
Ray...
Bloodlines or talent, having those things
from birth is a wonderful thing.
But that's not everything.
Effort and the right
environment are necessary, too.
All I did was end up in a good environment,
then simply live day by day.
Shake off your doubts and
take a new look at yourself.
By now you understand, right?
Once we are aware,
we can start anything over.
You're the only one who can provide
yourself with the answer you seek.
What I needed in my life
wasn't to hate people,
it was to accept people...
You're going to become much
stronger after this, Albert.
Thank you, Ray.
One of our staff members has
left us for personal reasons,
so let me introduce you to the new teacher
who will be replacing Helena Grady.
Why hello there, everyone!
That is right, I will be
your homeroom teacher!
My name is Carol Caroline!
Feel free to call me Caro,
or Carocaro, or Miss Carolin.
Teehee!
S-Say what?!
Looking forward to working with you all!
The Iceblade Sorcerer
Shall Rule the World
~ Next Episode Preview ~
Listen, this is the preview
of the next episode of
The Iceblade Sorcerer Shall Rule the World!
With the upcoming tournament to
determine the strongest student,
Amelia is quite harsh on herself.
Is the one who appears before
her as she struggles against
her preordained fate a devil or an angel?!
"The Boy Who Became the World's
Strongest Sorcerer Dons a Mask".
Episode 6
The Boy Who Became the World's Strongest Sorcerer Dons a Mask
This was Lydia Ainsworth!